# CHIARA SARTA

Ruby on Rails Developer

#### Personal information

Chiara Sarta chiara.sarta@gmail.com Schillerpromenade 7, 12049 Berlin +49 177 345 2557 - +49 030 25563055

### About me

I am a developer who loves exploring the power of different languages, and creating poetry within them. I believe in the beauty of code. I am curious, passionate about discovery and eager to learn new things everyday. After working as a frontend programmer for almost six years, I decided to take the challenge to become a backend developer. With three years full time experience, I have become a Ruby on Rails enthusiast, while still looking for new interesting challenges to learn from.

### **Expertise**

- Ability to work with vast, real-world apps, on both the backend and frontend side
- Self-motivated and autonomous worker with strong focus on business goals and end-user experience.
- In-depth understanding of Web 2.0, interface design and user experience
- Excellent capability to relate to people and work in a team
- Great organizational and scheduling skills.
- Curious and always eager to learn and explore

#### Technical skills

- TDD with Ruby on Rails and RSpec
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, TransactSQL
- Expert in hand-written CSS and HTML code, as well as with frameworks
- Working knowledge of PHP
- Working knowledge of Javascript, JQuery, CoffeeScript
- Git
- Experience with Heroku
- Currently learning Elixir and Phoenix

## **Work Experience**

July 2014 - February 2016

Backend developer

Autobutler gmbH, Berlin and Copenhagen

During the almost two years I worked at Autobutler I developed and consolidated my skills a lot, working in both the Autobutler site and the API and taking active part in a lot of projects. I implemented integrations with external services, working with third party APIs as well as with the Autobutler iPhone app and I had a lead role in the integration of a different marketing tool for communication with the users.

December 2012 - June 2014

Junior backend developer / Frontend developer WorkHub gmbH, Berlin

During my year at Workhub I have been developing a number of features for our community, as well as for the admin section and the project managers. I took responsibility of the namespacing of the main app into a separate engine, and upgraded the app to use the current Bootstrap version. I worked a lot with background jobs and scheduling, been hands deep in the production database, and wrote a lot of RSpec tests for my code. I have also been very much involved in reviewing code and the deployment process, and I got to use Amazon S3 tools.

September 2007 - Aprile 2013 Freelance Web developer with focus on frontend

Different companies and own customers

For over five years I worked as a freelance developer, both collaborating with a number of agencies in Italy, Germany and the US and managing my own clients.

My focus was the frontend during my collaborations with agencies.

For the projects where I worked directly with clients I took care of all phases and aspects of the required project: the necessary backend effort, the project managing and the relation to the client.

ing and the relation to the chem

#### Education

September 2006 - July 2007 Master Degree Visual and Web Design

Scuola Politecnica di Design, Milano

September 1999 - March 2006 Master Degree Communication Studies

Università degli Studi Di Torino

Final thesis in web development

September 1994 - June 1999 A-level, Math/Physics/Science

## Language skills

Italian Functionally Native Proficiency
English Advanced Professional Proficiency
German General Professional Proficiency
Panish Flamontary Proficiency

Danish Elementary Proficiency Finnish Elementary Proficiency

#### **Interests**

Music and photography: From 2008 till 2013 I collaborated with Heiko Laschitz-ki as assistant during photo shoots for music and fashion.

I actively contributed as photographer and writer for the online music magazine Slamrocks! between 2000 and 2003 and for the punk rock fanzine

Pankerknacker between 2008 and 2010.

I love reading, independent movies and board games.